

## **PROFILE**

Master's degree in marine engineering and bachelor's degree from faculty of natural science, mathematics computer science department. I am an Innovative software engineer offering over ten years of experience in the entire software development lifecycle – from concept through delivery of applications and customizable solutions. I have been developing a system for KRATC, CB&I (USA), HMSREG (Oslo Kommune), VaultSpeed, GoodTill, Banks, Chevron, and an in-house business system. I can analyse code and engineer well-researched, costeffective, and responsive solutions. I can quickly acquire the knowledge you need for the task at hand.

## CONTACT



**Phone** +370<u>67350586</u>





evaldas.laureckas@gmail.com



Linkedin

LinkedIn/evaldas



GitHub

GitHub/piratuks, GitHub/portfolio



Address

Lithuania, Klaipėda, Slengių village, Žvaigždyno 11-2

## **EXPERTISE**

- .NET (VB.NET & C#)
- Xamarin forms, ASP.NET
- PHP, Android (Java), TypeScript
- JavaScript (jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap, Node, KnockoutJS, Vue, React)
- WebSocket, Ajax
- HTML/CSS (SASS, Less, SCSS)
- MySQL, Microsoft T-SQL
- MongoDB, Trello, Jira
- MVC (Model, view, controller, Domain-driven design)
- Ionic framework, Cordova
- Objective-c/swift, UIAutomation
- Speech integrations
- FE modern frameworks

# **EVALDAS LAURECKAS**

**Application Engineer** 



## **KEY STRENGTHS**

- Analysing end-user needs and then developing software to meet their needs.
- Developing features across multiple applications.
- Reviewing code for quality and adherence to standards.
- Responding promptly to reports of bugs.
- Service level reporting.
- Communicating technical concepts.
- Maintaining proper software configuration management.
- Ensuring proper source code documentation.
- · Continuous deployment.
- Have experience in fully remote job/positions.
- Experience in leading the team.
- Experience in teams within Enterprise / Start-up setup.



## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

\_\_\_

Application Engineer

Chevron Corporation (USA Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. Work with JavaScript, node.js, angular 13 SASS/SCSS, Rest API, OAuth, Azure DevOps, angular material, Typescript, Python, Docker, Unit tests, ngrx state management, leaflet, microservices, stac-api).

### Projects are undertaken while with Chevron Corporation:

 Chevron Atlas – a project which combines a rapidly growing catalog of Chevronowned geospatial data with intuitive APIs, interactive exploration, and searchability to provide users with valuable insights into their data.

## Senior Front End Developer

Feb 2021 - Feb 2023

Dec 2022 - Present

Danske Bank A/S (Danish Bank) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

New project creation is a platform for risk officers to manage requirements presented to companies / individual persons as manual or automated questionnaires based on companies/person country's laws. Work with angular, ajax, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Node.js, Azure (pipelines), SASS, Restful, Typescript, angular material, docker, OpenShift, .NET, Unit tests, Selenium, SonarQube, BlackDuck, react, redux, ngrx state management, Sapphire (company's react framework).

#### Projects are undertaken while with Danske Bank A/S:

- Anti-money laundering project (tribe) Requirement management squad, a key name for the project is Cobra CRA. The platform for risk officers to create/edit/review requirements, and contexts. Option to publish/archive it, versioning of requirements.
- Anti-money laundering project (tribe) Transactional Assessment squad. The platform for risk officer overview other platform data.

## Full Stack JavaScript Developer Lead Front-End Developer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2023

VaultSpeed - The Agile Information Factory (Belgium Company, Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. Work with JavaScript, node.js & express, angularjs/angular2+, gulp, SASS/SCSS. Rest API, OAuth, Slack, Bitbucket, Git, Jira, Vis.js, semantic-ui, SCRUM, Big Data, Data Warehouse, Data Vault 2.0, Postgres, SQL Server, Oracle, T-SQL, Typescript, Monaco editor integration with custom language, mxGraph integration, Monaco

# EVALDAS LAURECKAS

**Application Engineer** 

## **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree in Engineering of Technological Information Systems Faculty of Marine Engineering 2013 – 2015

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics

Faculty of Natural Science & Mathematics Computer Science Department 2009 – 2013

#### **High School**

Kretinga Marijonas Daujotas Secondary School 1997 – 2009

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

 70-461 Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012 / 2014 - Passed, Score 700

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Business Process Modelling and Simulation: Aspect of Resources Modelling Problems. http://jmk.infotech.vgtu.lt/
- Analysis of Using Resources in Business Process Modelling and Simulation https://sciendo.com

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Problem-solver
- Excellent Communication
- Time management skills
- Leadership Ability
- Multi-tasking
- Attention to details
- Creativity
- Strong work ethics
- Interpersonal skills
- Positive Attitude
- Pressure Handling



## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

editor integration, Unit tests, Selenium tests, loopback 4, angular material, ngrx state management.

## Projects are undertaken while with VaultSpeed:

- Lots of improvements, features implementations, performance optimizations, and bug fixes under the company's leading product/platform for Data Vault 2.0.
- Customer support, respond to customer complaints/issues, and deal with them.
- Multiple dynamic, intuitive, user-friendly, graphical interface components implemented under canvas: Code names: Source Object Graphical Overview Editor, Satellites Split Graphical Editor, Bridges Graphical Editor, Template Graphical Editor, Source Data Vault Visualizer, Data Vault Graphical Editor.
- VaultSpeed studio.
- Pull request reviews, guiding other developers.
- Open-source project contributions.
- Project migration from angularjs to angular 12.
- Graphical component migrations from vis.js to mxGraph.
- API rework using loopback 4 to construct Restful.
- Loopback 4 API maintenance.
- Angular 12 FE maintenance.
- Participation in interviews for new Employees.

#### Full Stack JavaScript Developer

Aug 2020 - Apr 2021

Elsis Pro (Lithuanian Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Three of the products were running on old technologies. My primary investment in these projects was to upgrade the FE side with modern frameworks and ditch the Java (desktop app). Work with DevExtreme framework, angular, Java, Ajax, ActionScript, JBoss, Java Spring, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Node.js, Git, SASS, Restful, Typescript, Bootstrap, Python, SVN, SOAP.

#### Projects are undertaken while with Elsis Pro:

- Project code name (G/On Management) upgrade FE side. Migration from Java technology to Angular 10.
- Project code name (G/On Config) upgrade FE side. Migration from Java technology to Angular 10.
- Project code name (ENMA / EGNOS / NNMI network node manager) upgrade from adobe Flash / ActionScript (which is not supported anymore) to modern FE framework Angular 11. Also, keep the old BE with Java SOAP (that was the client's request). However, a wrapper with REST was created, which acted as a bridge between REST and SOAP.

#### App Developer

Jun 2018 - Jul 2019

The Good Till CO LTD (UK Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. All projects are designed for mobile devices. Most of them are for iOS, and a couple is for both Android and iOS. Work with ionic framework, angularjs/angular2+, firebase, bugs nag, web socket/sync, Cordova, web packs, java, Objective-c/swift, Ajax, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Node.js, Git, SASS, Gulp, PHP, Laravel, Vagrant, Restful, MySQL, Typescript.

#### Projects are undertaken while with The Good Till CO LTD:

- A developer of the company's main product, the POS system (Based point of sale system).
  - o iOS version: https://itunes.apple.com/lt/app/goodtill/id1116407057?mt=8
- A developer of the company's sub-project, such as an admin app.
  - o iOS version: https://itunes.apple.com/goodtill-admin/id1218479938?mt=8
  - o Android version: https://play.google.com/details?id=com.thegoodtill.admin
- A developer of the company's sub-project such as a loyalty app.
  - iOS version: https://itunes.apple.com/goodies/id1434560257?mt=8
     Android Version: https://play.google.com/details?id=com.thegoodtill.loyalty
- A developer of the company's sub-project such as the loyalty app.
  - o https://weborder.thegoodtill.com/

## EVALDAS LAURECKAS

**Application Engineer** 

## LANGUAGES

- LithuanianMother tongue
- English
   Fluent written and oral
   C1-Advanced
- RussianBasics
- German Basics

## PERSONAL INFO

- Date of birth: 25/11/1990
- Marital Status:
   Married
- Nationality: Lithuanian
- City: Klaipėdos r.
- Driving licenses:B (more than 12 years)



## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Integrations with Square payment, Curl payment systems, iZettle payment systems, Yoyo payment systems, Fourth Hospitality system, and other popular payment systems.

#### Developer

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

PCByVoice LTD (UK Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. Projects are a target for disabled people. They can use browsers/windows with only voice, etc. Work with UIAutomation, speech integrations, C#, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, SASS, jQuery, HTML, and Git.

#### Projects are undertaken while with PCByVoice LTD:

- A developer for Firefox and Chrome extensions called pcbynumbers. This
  extension repeatedly checks the active page. It marks all the page elements by
  numbers (these numbers are added under the page's layout. The style, opacity,
  colors, etc., are possible to change by the user). There is an active function under
  this extension. You use that active function by saying you want to use the
  number 4 from the page. This function focuses/clicks mentioned number. This
  extension is integrated with companies' speech integration which makes it
  possible to use extension by voice.
- A developer for the application called SpeechStart Pro. It allows using windows
  for hands-free users. It is marking each element on the active window with
  numbers that are activated by voice commands. Voice commands are coming
  from the company's speech integration. The old version can be checked here
  http://www.pcbyvoice.com/shop/pcbyvoice-speechstart-plus/

### Full Stack .NET Developer

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

STMCB Limited t/a Inspiratia (UK Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. Work with .NET (ASP, C#, Visual basic), SQL/T-SQL, Rest web services, Entity Framework, Linq (Linq to SQL), Ajax, HTML, CSS, LESS, jQuery, JavaScript (ECMAScript 6), KnockoutJS, SSAS, Node.js, Gulp, Git, TFVC, Jira, MVC (Model, view, controller. Domain-driven design).

#### Projects are undertaken whilst with Inspiratia:

- A developer of in-house systems.
  - http://icms.inspiratia.com/ -> in house CMS,
  - http://sms.inspiratia.com/ -> in house CMS,
  - https://www.inspiratia.com/ -> main project

### Software Systems Engineer

Mar 2013 - Jun 2018

UAB "Omega Technology" (Norwegian Company) (Omega AS, Onsite Job, Employment)

Maintenance of existing products. Testing and Corrections of issues for new and old projects. Design and implementation of new projects in teamwork and alone. Maintenance of company framework. Work with VB.NET, C#, ASP.NET, Ajax, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Less, Razor's script, Microsoft SQL Server, Appframe (Framework of the company), DevExpress, Bootstrap, jQuery, Flexpaper, customized Angular, Xamarin.

### Projects are undertaken while with UAB "Omega Technology":

- A developer for the KRATC project. This was a website and WinForms application
  for the Urban Waste Centre of Klaipėda Region. The project aimed to implement
  an automatic invoice generator and management of the invoices. It has been
  created <a href="https://mano.kratc.lt">https://mano.kratc.lt</a> for KRATC customers and a windows application for
  KRATC.
- A developer for the DCS (document control system) for "Statoil" (a Norwegian multinational oil and gas company). The project's purpose was to implement a document review system, approval system, history system, and management.
- A developer for the MCE project. The project aimed to implement an automatic schedule generator and document manager.

# EVALDAS LAURECKAS

**Application Engineer** 

## **REFERENCES**

- Animesh Chowdhury
   Director of The Good Till Co Ltd,
   Email: ani@thegoodtill.com
- Lindsay Adam
   Director of PCByVoice Ltd,
   Email: lindsay@pcbyvoice.com
- **Žilvinas Grigonis**Product Owner at Soliton Systems Inc.,
  Email: zilgrg@gmail.com
- Ravi Sejling
   Project Owner at Danske Bank
   Email: rsej@danskebank.dk
- Nuno Santos
   VaultSpeed Development
   Team Manager
   Email: nuno.santos@vaultspeed.com
- Dirk Vermeiren
   CTO for VaultSpeed
   Email:dirk.vermeiren@vaultspeed.com

## PERSONAL INTERESTS

I have a keen interest in IT and improving my knowledge outside of work (playing with different technologies, reading books/blogs, etc.). I participate in extreme activities such as bungee jumps, skydiving, snowboarding, etc.



## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- A developer for the Pims TAP project. The created solution is to export data from SharePoint and import it into the project database based on tables. I merged multiple databases into one.
- Was responsible for the three specific parts of the company framework. Worked with DevExpress reports and WinForms, dlls, web sites, and web technologies such as jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ASP.NET, CSS, HTML, Ajax.
- Was responsible for a website that includes an issue tracker, team docs, agenda, etc. The website used a framework and was used by Omega. Clients use different site versions. I had to support all versions. Technologies: JavaScript, Bootstrap, Font-Awesome, ASP.NET, CSS, HTML, LESS, Aspose, etc.
- A developer for a Cost Management system dedicated to CB&I. This was mainly the WinForms solution. However, there were some small website apps.
- A developer for an house app called Connect Omega.
- A developer for the HMSREG project (Oslo Kommune). Was responsible for mobile applications. These applications were built on cross-platform (Xamarin forms) for iOS and Android. Also helped implement a website and windows client for HMSREG based on Omega's framework.
  - o Android version > Android APP
  - o iOS version > iOS APP

#### Web Developer

Jan 2015 - Feb 2015

Launchmen (USA Company) (Remote Job, Individual activity certificate)

Maintenance of existing project. Testing, designing, and developing new projects in a team and alone. Work with PHP, JavaScript, Ajax, HTML, CSS, LESS, jQuery, CakePHP, Photoshop, and repository systems such as GitHub, and WordPress.

#### Projects are undertaken while with Launchmen:

- A developer of Business Miracles Site Document a small advertising website http://www.businessmiracles.com.
- A developer of Funnel a small advertising website.
- A developer of a couple of small, simple pages Slice/Code.

#### The Trainee Programmer / Tester

Jun 2012 - Aug 2012

UAB "Omega Technology" (Norwegian company) (Omega AS, Onsite Job, Employment)

Software testing and its development, using .NET programming language and database. Company framework improvement works. Work with company framework, SQL Server, .NET, Android.

### Projects are undertaken while with UAB "Omega Technology":

Created quality assurance application prototype for Android. This prototype had
three parts. The First part is an Android application, and the second part is a web
service written in .NET, and the third part is the SQL server database. The
purpose of this application is to quickly checklist of specific objects with a mobile
phone or touchpad to ensure that things meet their requirements.

### Web Developer

Sep 2012 - Sep 2012

VŠĮ Technology and Business School (Onsite Job, Employment)

Development of a new website for the school. Work with PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Yii framework, and jQuery.

#### Projects are undertaken while with VŠĮ Technology and Business School:

 Created the website of a school. The purpose of this project is to represent the school and its information through a website.

#### The auxiliary worker

Jun 2009 - Aug 2009

Construction companies (Onsite Job, Employment)

Auxiliary worker for construction companies at construction sites.

## Projects are undertaken with Construction companies:

• One of the builders who helped to build a house in Šventoji.